careergirldaily.com 2019-12-31

# Privacy Policy - Career Girl Daily

**CAREERGIRLDAILY.COM PRIVACY AND COOKIES POLICY**

Careergirldaily.com understands that your privacy is vitally important. We respect and value the privacy of everyone who visits our website and will only collect and use information in ways that are useful to you and are consistent with your rights and our obligations under the law.

This Policy applies to our use of all data we collect in relation to your use of our website. Please read this Policy carefully and ensure that you understand it. Your acceptance of this Privacy and Cookies Policy is deemed to occur upon your first use of our website. If you do not accept and agree with this Policy, you must stop using our website.

  *  **Definitions**

In this Policy, the following terms shall have the following meanings:  

 **“Account”**|  means an account required to access and/or use certain areas and features of our Site;  
---|---  
 **“Cookie”**|  means a small text file placed on your computer or device by our Site when you visit certain parts of our Site and/or when you use certain features of our Site;  
 **“EEA”**|  means the European Economic Area, comprised of all EU member states plus Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein;  
 **“Privacy Regulations”**|  means the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 as amended in 2004, 2011 and 2015;  
 **“Site”**|  means this website, CareerGirlDaily.com;  
 **“UK and EU Cookie Law”**|  means the relevant parts of the Privacy Regulations; and  
 **“we/us/our”**|  means Career Girl Daily London Ltd trading as CareerGirlDaily.com, a limited company registered in England and Wales with number **11045894** and whose registered office address is Office 15-3812 Vertinum 51 Portland Road, Kingston Upon Thames, Surrey, KT1 2SH.  
  
  *  **What does this Policy cover?**

This Policy applies only to your use of our Site. It does not extend to any websites that are linked to from our Site. We have no control over how your data is collected, stored or used by other websites: you should check the privacy policies of such websites before providing any data to them.

  *  **What is personal data?**

Personal data is defined by the General Data Protection Regulation (EU Regulation 2016/679) (the “ **GDPR** ”) as “any information relating to an identifiable person who can be directly or indirectly identified in particular by reference to an identifier”.

Personal data is any information about you that enables you to be identified. Personal data covers obvious information such as your name and contact details, but it also covers less obvious information such as identification numbers, electronic location data and other online identifiers.

  *  **What are my rights?**

Under the GDPR, you have the following rights, which we will always work to uphold:

  1.     1.       1.         1. the right to be informed about our collection and use of your personal data. This Privacy Policy should tell you everything you need to know, but you can always contact us to find out more or to ask any questions using the details in Clause 14;
        2. the right to access the personal data we hold about you. Clause 12 tells you how to do this;
        3. the right to have your personal data rectified if any of your personal data held by us is inaccurate or incomplete. Please contact us using the details in Clause 14 to find out more;
        4. the right to be forgotten, i.e. the right to ask us to delete or otherwise dispose of any of your personal data that we have. Please contact us using the details in Clause 14 to find out more;
        5. the right to restrict (i.e. prevent) the processing of your personal data;
        6. the right to object to us using your personal data for a particular purpose or purposes;
        7. the right to data portability. This means that if you have provided personal data to us directly, we are using it with your consent or for the performance of a contract and that data is processed using automated means, you can ask us for a copy of that personal data to re-use with another service or business in many cases; and
        8. rights relating to automated decision-making and profiling. We do not use your personal data in this way.

Further information about your rights can also be obtained from the Information Commissioner’s Office or your local Citizens Advice Bureau.

If you have any cause for complaint about our use of your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office.

  *  **What data do we collect?**

Some data is collected automatically by our Site. Other data is only collected if you voluntarily submit it (for example, when signing up for an Account). Depending upon your use of our Site, we may collect some or all of the following personal and non-personal data:

  * your name;
  * your gender;
  * your address;
  * your email address;
  * your telephone number;
  * information about your preferences and interests;
  * your IP address (automatically collected);
  * your web browser type and version (automatically collected);
  * your operating system (automatically collected);
  * a list of URLs starting with a referring site, your activity on our Site, and the site you exit to (automatically collected);

 **How we use your personal data**

Under the GDPR, we must always have a lawful basis for using personal data. This may be because the data is necessary for our performance of a contract with you, because you have consented to our use of your personal data, or because it is in our legitimate business interests to use it. Your personal data may be used for one or more of the following purposes:

  * providing and managing your Account;
  * providing and managing your access to our Site;
  * personalising and tailoring your experience on our Site;
  * personalising and tailoring our products and/or services for you;
  * communicating with you (for example, responding to emails or calls from you);
  * supplying you with information you have opted-in to (you may unsubscribe or opt-out at any time);
  * analysing your use of our Site to enable us to continually improve our Site and your user experience.

With your permission and/or where permitted by law, we may also use your personal data for marketing purposes, which may include contacting you by email with information, news, and offers on our products and/or services. You will not be sent any unlawful marketing or spam. We will always work to fully protect your rights and comply with our obligations under the GDPR and the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003, and you will always have the opportunity to opt-out.

  *  **How long we keep your data**

We will not keep your personal data for any longer than is necessary in light of the reason(s) for which it was first collected. The following factors will be used to determine how long it is kept:

  * When no longer needed in light of the reason(s) which it was first collected.

 **How and where we store or transfer your data**

We will only store or transfer your personal data within the EEA. This means that it will be fully protected under the GDPR or to equivalent standards by law.

Where we transfer your data to a third party based in the United States of America, this may be protected if they are part of the EU-US Privacy Shield. This requires that third party to provide data protection to standards similar to those in Europe. More information is available from the [European Commission](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/eu-us-privacy-shield_en).

Data security is of great importance to us, and to protect your data we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure data collected through our Site.

Notwithstanding the security measures we take, the transmission of data via the internet may not be completely secure. You should always take suitable precautions when transmitting data via the internet.

  *  **Do we share your data?**

We do not share your data to third parties unless we have your permission to do so.

We may compile statistics about the use of our Site including data on traffic, usage patterns, user numbers, sales and other information. All such data will be anonymised and will not include any personally identifying information. We may from time to time share such data with third parties such as prospective investors, affiliates, partners and advertisers. Data will only be shared and used within the bounds of the law.

In certain circumstances, we may be legally obliged to share data held by us, which may include your personal information – for example, where we are involved in legal proceedings, or where we are complying with the requirements of legislation, a court order or a governmental authority. We do not require any further permission from you in order to share your data in such circumstances and will comply as required with any such legally binding request that is made of us.

  *  **How you can control your data**

In addition to your rights under the GDPR, when you submit personal data via our Site, you may be given options to restrict our use of your personal data. In particular, we aim to give you strong controls on our use of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including the ability to opt-out of receiving emails from us which you may do by unsubscribing using the links provided in our emails **)**.

You may also wish to sign up to one or more of the preference services operating in the UK: the Telephone Preference Service, the Corporate Telephone Preference Service, and the Mailing Preference Service. These may help to prevent you receiving unsolicited marketing. Please note, however, that these services will not prevent you from receiving marketing communications that you have consented to receiving.

  *  **How you can withhold information**

You may access parts of our Site without providing any data at all.

You may restrict your web browser’s use of Cookies. For more information, see clause 13.

  *  **How you can access your data**

If you want to know what personal data we have about you, you can ask us for details of that personal data and for a copy of it (where any such personal data is held). This is known as a “subject access request”.

All subject access requests should be made in writing and sent by to the email or postal address shown in clause 14. 

There is not normally any charge for a subject access request. However, if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive (for example, if you make repetitive requests) we may charge a fee to cover our administrative costs in responding.

We will respond to your subject access request within one month of receiving it. Normally, we aim to provide a complete response, including a copy of your personal data, within that time. In some cases, however, particularly if your request is more complex, more time may be required up to a maximum of three months from the date we receive your request and, if relevant, your fee.

  *  **How we use Cookies**

Our Site may place and access certain Cookies on your computer or device. We use Cookies to facilitate and improve your experience of our Site, to provide and improve our products and/or services, and to analyse traffic to our Site. We have carefully chosen these Cookies and have taken steps to ensure your privacy and personal data is protected and respected at all times.

By using our Site, you may also receive certain third-party Cookies on your computer or device. Third-party Cookies are those placed by websites, services and/or parties other than us. Third-party Cookies are used on our Site by third-party advertisers. These Cookies are not integral to the functioning of our Site and your use and experience of our Site will not be impaired by refusing consent to them.

All Cookies used by and on our Site are used in accordance with current UK and EU Cookie Law.

Before Cookies are placed on your computer or device, you will be shown a  pop-up requesting your consent to set those Cookies. By giving your consent to the placing of Cookies you are enabling us to provide the best possible experience and service to you. You may, if you wish, deny consent to the placing of Cookies; however, certain features of our Site may then not function fully or as intended. 

Our Site uses analytics services provided by Google Analytics & Kinsta. Website analytics refers to a set of tools used to collect and analyse anonymous usage information, enabling us to better understand how our Site is used. This, in turn, enables us to improve our Site and the products and/or services offered through it.

The analytics service(s) used by our Site use(s) Cookies to gather the required information. You do not have to allow us to use these Cookies; however, while our use of them does not pose any risk to your privacy or your safe use of our Site, it does enable us to continually improve our Site, making it a better and more useful experience for you.

You can choose to enable or disable Cookies in your internet browser. Most browsers also enable you to choose whether you wish to disable all Cookies or only third-party Cookies. By default, most internet browsers accept Cookies, but this can be changed. For further details, please consult the help menu in your browser or the documentation that came with your device.

You can choose to delete Cookies on your computer or device at any time; however, you may lose any information that enables you to access our Site more quickly and efficiently including (but not limited to) login and personalisation settings.

You should keep your browser and operating system up-to-date and consult the help and guidance provided by the developer of your browser and manufacturer of your computer or device if you are unsure about adjusting your privacy settings.

  *  **Contacting us**

If you have any questions about our Site or this Policy, please contact us by email at info@cgdlondon.com.

  *  **Changes to this Policy**

We may change this Policy as we may deem necessary from time to time, or as may be required by law. Any changes will be posted on our Site and you will be deemed to have accepted the revised Policy on your first use of our Site following the changes. You should therefore check this page regularly.
